hello everybody and welcome back to
another product review so today we're
talking secret weapon and they're a new
line of weathering paints so I picked
these up they were on pre-release you
can get them now from secret weapons
website as well I'm not sure if they've
really filtered out to a lot of other
stores but they are available there and
this is a really interesting range of
paints and I was really excited to get
my hands on them to use them some I've
been using them now since I've for a
couple weeks since I got back from a
devta con and I've thought hey let's get
a review up because I think they're
pretty cool and useful so there's kind
of a spoiler so there's several
different ranges to this I don't have
the whole range here this is just a
small sample of it there's a whole
rusting line there's a very dark this is
oh then there's old rust
this one's brown rust and then there's a
very light rust
most of these are three or four color
sets you've got a tire line which starts
with the actual like tire itself which
has a satin Sheen to it then it goes up
to the rubber which is sort of a gray
black and then the rubber highlight
there's also there's also an orange and
yellow rust in there to kind of
highlight everything as well as a whole
would set which includes like dark wood
handle wood weathered wood which looks
very grey for doing like old woods um
you could also use it as like your very
upper highlight on your tires and stuff
like that and then finally there's an
entire dirt cycle starting with like old
mud which has kind of a ruddy red tone
cake dirt and light dust okay so that's
kind of the whole deal if you get it
from secret weapon there are four
dollars piece
these come in 20 milliliter bottles
which i think is pretty reasonably
priced I mean it's pretty standard
they're good dropper bottles
they don't tend to clog look at that
there comes right out maybe a little too
much because I shook it a little too
hard that's my fault not the Paintsville
um but they're very interesting paints
because they don't all have a universal
texture and you can do very complex
effects with unusual things so for doing
like that caked on dirt type of look
onto stuff so they dry in a very
fascinating sort of way and I'm gonna
actually start painting with this as we
talk just as I continue with the review
so I'm just gonna put a little bit of
the old rust which is sort of a very
dark ruddy Brown out there there is a
darker color and I'm gonna grab some of
the brown rust we want to use some of
both of these okay okay and so um what's
interesting about them and we're just
gonna use you can see here we've got our
old friend the juggernaut he's just
completely metal so we're just gonna
rust him out and we're gonna do that by
just kind of stippling some of this on
we're gonna see how this goes and how it
looks when it's all applied and dries
and stuff like that so you can see that
has a very red tone to it right I don't
know if that really comes through on the
camera but I can tell you like in
reality that is a very very red tone to
that rust we're just gonna shove it down
here and the cracks and stuff of this
guy so as I said there's a whole big
range of it um the the trick with them
is that they do apply they have some
different textures so as I mentioned
before when you talk about something
like the base tire rubber that one has a
nice satin finish to it a little bit of
Sheen
you know like tires basically right
whereas when you go up into the rubber
in the very high light rubber what you
get is something more like dust okay so
it looks more like the chalky darkness
or sorry yeah the chalky grayness that's
what I would say uh your tires as they
drive down the road new cumulate you
know concrete dust and just everything
else that's there so um I think a lot of
these are great especially for you 40k
players out there anybody doing large
vehicles but they're also interesting in
that there you can see we've just kind
of just kind of threw some of that
around a shadow let's rinse that off
you're gonna let that kind of dry and
then I'm gonna just grab some of the
other rust color these are also
interesting to work in with your other
paints just because although some of
them have a texture the ones that don't
are very matte and the way that they
apply can can really make it a sort of
interesting painting experience to just
kind of use them you can see how these
are applying let's really take a look
here right like when I put this on you
can see how how that looks and it stays
fairly wet like I didn't do anything
this is straight out of the pot right it
stays fairly wet so I can really push
that around right I can really take
those weathering effects and kind of
scoot them draw them down into the
cracks you know whatever I want to do
which is nice the blacks and such has a
similar effect so I'm gonna flip that
over and I'm just gonna put some of the
black here on this side it's tire rubber
but that's okay we'll use it as though
we were shadowing this guy just so you
can see kind of how that looks
if we were gonna have the dark effect on
there because I really like these rubber
colors mixed into other paints and again
they have this very sort of very matte
quality to them they're they're really
these hyper matte colors because they're
all meant to be for weathering and so as
a result when you mix them in with other
paints when you thin other things out
you don't get any you know any
glossiness or anything like that okay so
you can see there that's a you know you
can create really nice shadow effects
with these because of the way that
they're very matte they just kind of
feather out really nicely right and
actually I've liked using them for that
purpose I've kind of I'm actually been
using them just as much to kind of
create to mix in with other paints or
just to help with some light shadows
some dark shadows stuff like that so
flipping this back around over here
which should be dry now you can see I
hope let's let's really try to zoom in
here I'll see how much I can do this
without and then clear that up
you can do it sorry I'm trying to get
really really tight there we go
perfect now stay
okay I try my best not to move too much
but you can see the texture of that so
if you look at the metallic paint and
then you look here right you see how dry
that texture is how rough and sort of
beaten that looks right
I really like that texture that it adds
if I flip it around here sorry you can
see how that's dried with those two
layers of rust and the difference in the
colors okay
let's flip it around we'll take a close
look at the gray does it dries in a
similar fashion again come on you can do
it and your focus there we go
um so I really love this for I really
love this effect on metals you can see
how it interacted with that metal to
just create a nice and dull like a
dullness to it right so if you want kind
of an old beaten look to your steel I
think this takes your your normal color
and you can see how it darkened it down
and dole it out it didn't really blacken
it right one of my problems with using
something like an old oil or something
is you're automatically blackening that
steel when that's not necessarily what I
want sometimes I just want the metal to
look old right weathered like it doesn't
nobody walked up to it and polished it
in a couple months and to me that's a
great effect you can see there when I
turn in the light the difference of how
it reflects the light so I really love
these rubber paints for that so that's a
rubber and rubber highlight they just
the way you can push him around and
feather them and work him another paints
I think it has are really fantastic you
can use it to sort of your shade color
to darken something down you can also
use it as an interesting extra effect on
your metal to create you know sort of
Aging and and where okay so there you go
all in all I really like these new
paints I think they're pretty great I
mean zoom back out here so I'm not
constantly tripping you up on focus I
really like these new paints I think
they're pretty great they they're very
easy to work with I think they're fairly
cost effective pretty standard at four
dollars for a twenty milliliter I think
they have a lot of uses both in
weathering and in just mixing in with
other paints though you do have to be
careful you can't use like these rust
things mixed into something you want to
be like cloth or smooth because it will
have a rough texture to it so it's great
if you're trying to do something
appropriately textured you mix this into
you know color you're doing for fur or
hair or something like that oh it's
beautiful it mattes it right out and it
gives it that sort of rough
texture that fur or hair would normally
have so I really like that like a
leather this stuff is just bonkers
awesome for doing leather actually the
whole range so I I do really love that
if you're trying to do like a really
dark rough natural leather um all in all
I think these paints are worth picking
up if you're into if you're into doing
weathering and stuff like that because
they also then have other uses you can
use them in your normal painting routine
I would say if you're not doing anything
that's weathering um then probably a
little lower on the priority just
because there's probably other things
you can get but if you're gonna be doing
a lot of vehicle work if you're gonna be
doing any kind of like big mechs or
dirty armies or anything like that I
think these are aces because not only
are they gonna excel at that but they're
gonna then work into the rest of your
rotation in some interesting ways so
overall I give these secret weapon
weathering a solid a - I think they're a
good value I think they're very useful
for what they're doing
understanding that the only caveat to
that a - is that you know you have to be
actually doing weathering to wreak and
recognize their full value or you know
doing rubber tires or caked on dirt or
stuff like that if you're print if
you're if your current project is a
bunch of shiny bright High Elves that
just brought their armor out of the
Smith well maybe give these a pass for
now but if you're trying to capture some
old beaten you know nerd alight force OH
give these a second look let me tell you
what I think you're gonna have some fun
with that so there you go a - overall
hope you enjoy the review as always
appreciate you watching and we'll see
you